RIYAS.V. B

Mobile: +973 34028521, E-Mail: riyasub@gmail.com

SNAP SHOT
~ Sales & Operations ~ Business Development ~
A result-oriented professional with nearly 12 years of consolidated experience in Sales, Distribution and Operations, Business Development etc.
Leading, training, and monitoring the performance of team members to ensure efficiency in sales operations and meeting of targets. Possess good administrative skills.
Excellent communicator with strong negotiation skills having leadership qualities and analytical skills.
Proactively conducting SWOT analysis by keeping abreast of market trends/competitor moves to achieve market-share metrics.
Drive the team to deliver cost effective rates.
CORE COMPETENCIES
Sales & Operations / Business Development
Developing marketing strategies to build consumer preference and driving volumes. Evaluating marketing budgets periodically including manpower planning initiatives and ensure adherence to planned expenses. Giving equal focus to all verticals and thereby driving volume and profitability. Driving and leading the Team to achieve targets and Goal sheets given by the company.
Distribution & Channel Management
Identifying financially & technically strong and reliable dealers resulting in deeper market penetration and reach. Evaluating performance & monitoring dealer s sales and marketing activities. Monitoring dealer sales & marketing activities; implementing effective strategies to maximize sales and accomplishment of revenue. Managing and driving new initiative at dealer network in line with strategic plan set.
Team Management
Leading, mentoring & monitoring the performance of the team to ensure efficiency in process operations & meeting of individual
 & group targets. Managing complete recruitment life cycle for sourcing the best talent from diverse sources after identification of manpower requirements.
ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS
Bachelor of Arts, Kurukshetra University, Alappuzha.2000-2003.
Pre- Degree, Kerala University, SD College Alappuzha.1998-2000.
SSLC Public Examinations Board GHS Mannanncherry 1997-1998

JOB HISTORY

Total work experience of 12 years in Sales, Distribution & Operations in Telecom	l.
ORGANISATION: IDEA MART SUPER MARKET GROUP, BAHRAIN	

FEB 2020 - TILL DATE

Business development manager.

ORGANISATION: RELIANCE JIO INFOCOMM LTD.

JUNE 2019 - DEC 2019.

Mobility Sales Lead at Reliance Jio Infocomm Ltd.

NATURE OF JOB:

- Responsible for the appointment of Distributors in the given territory.
- To guide and monitor Distributors in achieving their targets of Phones, Wi-Fi Devices and Sim Cards.
- Responsible for improving the Gross additions, URO, UAO, CMS and RMS.
- To help the Distributors in achieving their Primary, Secondary and Territory targets by driving sales Team.
- Handling total Business for this area and Distribution parameters and Sales managers of this designed area.

ORGANISATION: CUMULUSTECH MIDDLE EAST WLL, BAHRAIN

JULY 2018 May 2019.

Business Development Manager

NATURE OF JOB:

- Managing Sales of Mobile Phone Applications and Web Applications.
- Developing the business of all kinds of Software's.

ORGANISATION: XO CENTRAL, KINGDOM OF BAHRAIN.

OCTOBER 2017 JULY 2018

Sales Manager in XO Central, Kingdom of Bahrain NATURE OF JOB:

- Managing Sales of Mobile Phone Applications and Web Applications.
- Responsible for the Sales and Marketing of Websites Designing.

ORGANISATION: SISTEMA SHYAM TELESERVICES LTD.

JULY 2013 JULY 2017.

Area Sales Manager in Sistema Shyam teleservices Ltd.

NATURE OF JOB:

- Responsible for the appointment of Distributors in the given territory.
- To guide and monitor Distributors in achieving their targets of Data card sales.

Γ	
	Responsible for improving the Gross additions, UAO & URO.
Γ	To help the Distributors in achieving their Primary, Secondary and Territory targets by driving sales Team.
OPGAI	Handling prepaid distribution. NISATION: RELIANCE COMMUNICATIONS LTD.
OKOA	NISATION. RELIANCE COMMUNICATIONS LTD.
SEP 20	012 JULY 2013.
Territo	ory Sales Manager in Reliance communications Ltd.
NAT	URE OF JOB:
Γ	Responsible for the appointment of Distributors in the given territory.
Γ	To guide and monitor Distributors in achieving their targets.
Γ	Responsible for improving the Gross additions, UAO & URO.
Γ	To help the Distributors in achieving their Primary, Secondary and Territiary targets by driving sales Team Handling prepaid distribution.
ORGAN	VISATION: UNITECH WIRELESS LTD. (A Telenor Unitech
	·
Compar FEB 201	ny .
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu	1 AUG 2012.
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu directly	AUG 2012. the Company as Senior Executive, Sales & Distribution handling zha Area and reporting to the Zonal Manager. There are 4 Distributors, 15 RSEs and 8 KAMs
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu directly	1 AUG 2012. the Company as Senior Executive, Sales & Distribution handling zha Area and reporting to the Zonal Manager. There are 4 Distributors, 15 RSEs and 8 KAMs reporting to me. I have been promoted as Deputy Manager on last Appraisal.
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu directly	AUG 2012. the Company as Senior Executive, Sales & Distribution handling zha Area and reporting to the Zonal Manager. There are 4 Distributors, 15 RSEs and 8 KAMs reporting to me. I have been promoted as Deputy Manager on last Appraisal. RE OF JOB:
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu directly	AUG 2012. the Company as Senior Executive, Sales & Distribution handling zha Area and reporting to the Zonal Manager. There are 4 Distributors, 15 RSEs and 8 KAMs reporting to me. I have been promoted as Deputy Manager on last Appraisal. RE OF JOB: Responsible for the appointment of Distributors in the given territory.
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu directly	AUG 2012. the Company as Senior Executive, Sales & Distribution handling zha Area and reporting to the Zonal Manager. There are 4 Distributors, 15 RSEs and 8 KAMs reporting to me. I have been promoted as Deputy Manager on last Appraisal. RE OF JOB: Responsible for the appointment of Distributors in the given territory. To guide and monitor Distributors in achieving their targets.
Compar FEB 201 Joined Alappu directly	the Company as Senior Executive, Sales & Distribution handling zha Area and reporting to the Zonal Manager. There are 4 Distributors, 15 RSEs and 8 KAMs reporting to me. I have been promoted as Deputy Manager on last Appraisal. RE OF JOB: Responsible for the appointment of Distributors in the given territory. To guide and monitor Distributors in achieving their targets. Responsible for improving the Gross additions, UAO & URO. To help the Distributors in achieving their Primary, Secondary and Territiary targets by driving sales Team Announcing retailer schemes and ensuring 100% achievement and market settlement with in the stipulated

JULY 2008 FEB 2011.

Joined the Company as Senior Territory Sales Executive handling Alappuzha

Area.

These is 3 Distributors, 10 Sales staff and 3 Backend staff reporting to me.

NATURE OF JOB:

Γ	Responsible for all Sales and Operations of 3 Distributors.
Г	Responsible for Mobile, Net setter sales and Business. Distributor profitability is the main KRA.
Γ	Responsible for the Distributor wise Target VS Achievement of all products
Г	Achieve sales targets by designing and implementing effective promotions and campaigns. Proper training and education to all staff regarding latest offers and happenings of the Business.

PERSONAL DETAILS

FATHER'S NAME : V.A. BASHEER PERMANENT ADDRESS :

KOCHUVELIYIL,

MANNANCHERRY. P.O ALAPPUZHA DISTRICT, KERALA, PIN-688 538.

PRESENT ADDRESS : FLAT NO:14,URBAN COURT

ROAD:305,BLOCK;303

MANAMA, KINGDOME OF BAHRAIN

DATE OF BIRTH : 1st MAY 1983

NATIONALITY : INDIAN

PASSPORT NO : P6746743

LANGAUGES KNOWN : English, Tamil, Malayalam & Hindi.

INTERESTS : Music and Cricket

REFERENCE 1 : Mr. VIPIN.K.T DISTRIBUTION HEAD VODAFONE

QATAR Ph:

0097477775335.

REFERENCE 2 : Mr. DILEEP . T BUSINESS HEAD ETISALAT DUBAI.

Ph: 00971502000144

Place: Bahrain

Date: RIYAS.V.B